Divya Prakash

+91 7411405523 | d.prakash1506@gmail.com | Bengaluru, India 560037

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/divyaprakashdp | Portfolio: divyaprakashdp.github.io

SUMMARY

5 years of experience building responsive, user-focused applications for healthcare and e-commerce sectors. Background in multiple programming languages. Possess strong problem-solving skills, ability to quickly learn new software technologies. Previous work involved significant contribution to product development projects resulting in improved system functionality and user experience. Known for exceptional teamwork skills and commitment to maintaining up-to-date industry knowledge.

SKILLS

- Front End development
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- Redux
- Tailwind CSS
- HTML
- CSS
- Material UI
- · Agile methodologies

- Node.js
- Rest API
- GraphQL
- Typescript
- Git
- CI/CD
- Test Automation
- Selenium
- JIRA

EXPERIENCE

Consultant (Frontend Developer), Deloitte USI, October 2020 - Current

- Developed scalable solutions using JavaScript and ReactJS, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement.
- Created innovative micro-tools, reducing repetitive tasks, and enhancing productivity.
- Thrived in diverse tech stacks, rapidly acquiring new skills to meet client requirements.

Member of Technical Staff, MetricStream, August 2019 - October 2020

- Revamped R&D testing tool with object-oriented design patterns and SOLID principles for a robust solution.
- Created an API automation framework using JavaScript and Node.js for efficient automation.
- Proficiently utilized Java, JavaScript, Node.js, and JavaFX to deliver solutions.

Test Engineer, Emids, April 2017 - August 2020

- Worked on an electronic healthcare records application for an award-winning US-based health information technology vendor.
- Ensured top-notch quality by uncovering the highest number of defects in various sprints and promptly
 addressing and debugging the issues.
- Worked broadly on REST API, Test Automation, Debugging.

PROJECTS

BIBLIAI

Live: https://bibliai.netlify.app/

GIT:https://github.com/divyaprakashdp/bibliai

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.)

Rajiv Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal, M.P. 2015